<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-05-28T16:29:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2019/05/28/newsletter.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2019/05/28/newsletter.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-28T16:29:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-28T16:57:36-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello folks!
I've been toying with the idea for a while now of creating a sporadic method of publishing some updates, news, or info. I'm going to try for monthly, but it might change based on how often I create content worth publishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal will be a short newsletter with new projects, project updates, travel news, recommendations, and other writing. You'll be able to catch up on back letters on my blog, and I'll link more in-depth project updates that I post there. Theres a pretty wide array of areas of interest, so there's no telling what will be the from time to time, but it'll give me a good place to flex my writing muscles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/letters"&gt;Subscribe!&lt;/a&gt; And let's see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Vlog</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2018/11/01/new-video.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2018/11/01/new-video.html</id>
    <published>2018-11-01T12:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-21T11:55:48-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently just spent 5 weeks overseas for work, most of this time living out of a hotel by myself. The result of
doing this meant I had a lot of time  catching up on a lot of netflix and podcasts. So I tried something different
and made a vlog of some of the stuff I did. I didn't have anything better then my laptop webcam so I'm not super proud of the finished project, but it's a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q_-opCNGWYU" title="TV and Podcast review"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/Q_-opCNGWYU/0.jpg" alt="TV and Podcase review" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>France Vision Trip Part Two- Paris</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/07/17/france2.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/07/17/france2.html</id>
    <published>2017-07-17T16:14:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2018-10-17T06:35:39-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The train ride from Geneva to Paris was beautiful. Coming through the alps onto the plains was a sight to behold.  The Parisian train station was right next to the Notre Dame so we walked over there to meet our host for the second leg of the trip. Paul Robelot worked for TEAM in member care and described himself as a church planter by hobby. He drove us back to his house that night in the Paris suburbs. Paul and his family lived in the beautiful farmland outside of the Paris core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the Paris leg doing several different kinds of activities. One of our first days we went and worked with a  missionary who had a relationship with a local Imam. He took us to the mosque to meet the Imam and we got a tour of the mosque. It was Kurdish mosque, and it was very interesting to hear how this group had struggled against persecution from other Turkish groups. It was a great opportunity to ask questions about Islam and the different practicies. We ended the tour being served tea and gifted a Quran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That same night, we went to a evening service focused on welcoming refugees from the area. A handful of guys showed up and we went around the room introducing out selves and telling our stories. It was amazing hear the journeys these guys had made to escape the struggles in their home communities. It closed with a short message about Jesus being more then a prophet, but our messiah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Paul's close associates, Bill Bogges, was the TEAM leader who had been in charge of the entire France region. He and his wife were preparing to retire back to the states and hand things off to Jon(who we met in Bonneville) at the end of the year. We got to spend a lot of time with Bill hearing how France had changed in the last ~30 years. He also spent a day showing us around the city and talking about life and community in the area. It was a good chance to ask a lot of logistic questions about living in France, going to school there, meeting people, and sharing the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several times during this leg we got to sit with missionaries who ran different programs. I got well versed in sharing my story and why I was there in France meeting them. One of the important things I came to realize in those visits was how important it was to the people were visiting. Several times the local ministers were brought to tears just explaining they had never had visitors from the states come listen to their testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big aspect for me for this leg was feeling the grind of living life in this region. Because Paris is such a big town(with a lot of traffic) we spent a lot of time sitting in cars delayed by accidents or other things that happen in large cities. Missed meals were commonplace, as we prioritized time with locals over getting to a restaurant before it closed. In a city like Paris it is very easy to romanticize living there without realizing the struggles that come with living in such a place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the final days here we went to Trappes. Trappes is a Parisian suburb which is thought to be 98% Muslim. It was like entering a North African community, full of people in African garb, an giant open-air market akin to the Souks you would find in Morrocco, and all the smells that would go along with it. We met up with Sam who, along his family, had felt called to minister to this area. It was the day before Ramadan started, and the large market in the center of the city was filled with people preparing. Sam showed us around the market while we talked about different elements of sharing the gospel with Muslim populations. He also graciously invited us to his home and prepared some food and tea while him and his wife told us their story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was so much beauty to witness in this entire trip. God's people are so full of joy no matter where on earth they live, and that commonality transcends any earthly comparison. I don't know what my next steps would be in this journey; I'm currently taking stock of possible options and where next I could go. I thank you for taking time to read this, and participate in my story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/blog/2017/07/07/france-trip-part-one.html"&gt;Part one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>France Vision Trip Part One - Geneva</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/07/07/france-trip-part-one.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/07/07/france-trip-part-one.html</id>
    <published>2017-07-06T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2018-10-17T06:35:39-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My time in Geneva was a powerful start to the France Vision Trip. We stayed in a mountain chalet in the French Alps near the town of Bonneville. Hiking trails out my front door, picturesque roads passing cows, and stunning views. Bonneville is in a valley situated in the French Prealps. It's a small community, mostly of people who commute daily to work in nearby Geneva. Our local host, Jon, built an excellent plan to introduce us to the local communities. Our first day was a Sunday so we went to a local church gathering in Geneva. Once a year 5 churches in the area hold a gathering together where they fellowship, listen to a sermon, and then have a potluck lunch. Our visit just happened to coincide with this yearly event.  Even though I could barely follow along with the music and sermon, it brought joy to my heart to see people worshiping Jesus.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We kicked the week off spending some time in a park that, one one side over looked the city of Geneva, and the other side gave a beautiful view of the valley we were staying in and on a clear day(like that day was) you can see Mont Blanc, the high point of the alps, and  Lac Léman from the same vantage point. We packed a lunch and spent a few hours alone in this park having some time to pray, journal, and read scriptures in preparation for the trip. This was an excellent way to begin the trip in a right state of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the week in this area was traveling around the area and visiting with missionaries, relief workers, and pastors. Our group had a rental car that we took around the valley and it allowed us to bond as a team by spending time in the car sharing our stories as we traveled. Listening to peoples stories of their faith is such a beautiful reminder of work being done in the name of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the last things we did in the area was visit Crossroads church which was situated on the French side of the borders, just meters from the Geneva airport. Here we listened to Katie's story of how she felt God calling her to minister to a local group of Roma Gypsies in her backyard. These were people who had been outcast, mistreated, and even suffered government persecution in finding sustainable employment. They were living out of cars or squatting in abandoned buildings just a few minutes walk from the church. Katie had started walking over to them and building a relationship with them, even though they mostly didn't speak French or English and she spoke no Romanian or Italian. After Katie told us her story she invited us to walk over with her to meet them. We were fortunate there was a woman there who could speak some English so we spent that afternoon talking with her and hearing her story. Watching Katie work through the difficulties and obstacles to just share love and the Gospel with her neighbors was a powerful reminder that nothing should stop us from where God sends us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we finished here we hopped on a train and set off for Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/blog/2017/07/17/france2.html"&gt;Part two&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>France Trip Begins!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/05/13/france-trip-begins.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/05/13/france-trip-begins.html</id>
    <published>2017-05-12T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2018-10-17T06:35:39-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The time is here. We leave Portland Friday evening on May 12th headed to Geneva. There we will meet the team and spend a week in the area visiting with missionaries, outreach programs, and marinating one community while we pray and seek God’s wisdom. Well then move on to Paris for a week with a similar plan there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in a different place today then I was when I first set down this road. No matter how often you hear stories about your life not following any plan, we all fall into that trap. It emphasized even more the need to spend this time with a completely open heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Many are the plans in a person’s heart, but it is the Lord’s purpose that prevails.” – Proverbs 19:21&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to post some updates on this blog, but also follow along on Twitter @kmartinix
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Upcoming Trip to France</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/03/13/france-trip.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/03/13/france-trip.html</id>
    <published>2017-03-12T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2018-10-17T06:35:39-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may recall from our previous letter, “Martin Update“, Kendrick and I are planning a trip this May to France with TEAM (https://team.org/) to go on a short-term or “Vision casting” trip. The main goal of this trip is relationship building and working with permanent missions teams located there. It is our goal to prayerfully seek GoIMG_20160624_141708.jpgd’s will in how we can use our talents to build and extend His Kingdom, and share God’s love in practical ways. As you may have heard, there is a massive influx of refugees in Europe, and that number isn’t going down anytime soon. These people are coming from a wide array of backgrounds, and have an even wider set of needs. In addition, the French country has a growing number of Muslim immigrants moving from various nations around the world. Couple this with the fact that France is one of the leading post-Christian and post-Catholic communities in the world, and you have a huge need for the Gospel. Years ago, Kendrick was moved by a sermon about the need for missionaries in France and since then he has felt that we would end up there someday. It is our hope that we can utilize our love of community building, and supporting marginalized people groups to strengthen the Church by showing Christ’s love in practical, relational ways.

The Lord has been preparing us in so many different ways over the past couple years. I have been attending missions conferences, learning more about the refugee crisis domestically and globally. I’ve also been learning a great deal at Portland IMG_20160624_122620.jpgRescue Mission as I work with broken women trying to get their lives back from addiction, abuse and heartbreak. Kendrick feels especially called toward discipleship and he has pursued this ferociously
. He’s been meeting with multiple small groups of guys on a weekly basis for some time. Whether it’s book clubs or Bible studies, their consistent purpose is to enrich each other’s lives through community focused on Jesus Christ. I am so proud of his commitment to consistent discipleship and I’ve learned so much from his example. We’ve also been volunteering together at Portland Rescue Mission for the past two years and took over the leadership of our volunteer group this past year. On a monthly basis, we help serve a meal and share the gospel in a short chapel service. Here’s some verses we’re meditating on in preparation for our trip: Genesis 12:1-3; Matthew 28:18-20; Luke 24:45-49; Revelation 7:9-10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to have you join us on this journey. Since the main goal of this trip is fact finding and seeking a longer-term vision, prayer is a huge part of that. We both ask you to keep us in your daily prayers, to keep our minds and hearts focused and listening to whatever God is calling us to. We are also in need of financial support to make this trip happen. Our budget is $4,556.60 and we need to raise that by April 22nd. We’re committing to cover just about half of that and trust the Lord to provide the rest. We’d like to ask you to partner with us in meeting our goal of raising $2,300 in this next month and a half. Whether you can afford $10 or $100, it would make a huge difference for us if you joined us financially and prayerfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to give is online, follow the link below and enter “Martin” into the search. Then we should pop up as Martin, Kendrick &amp;amp; Emily – 012165. You can choose to give once or at a few different frequencies. When you give online, your donation is automatically tax deductible.  You can also donate cash or check by mail and we’ll submit your donation to TEAM on your behalf. https://secure2.convio.net/team/site/SPageServer?pagename=donatenow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no fear in love. But perfect love drives out fear, because fear has to do with punishment. The one who fears is not made perfect in love. We love because he first loved us. 1 John 4:18-19&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
